Finding Aid for Washtenaw United Way Records, 1921-2001
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Washtenaw United Way records
1921-2001
Washtenaw United Way.
85456 Bj 2; BJ Outsize
Records of the Washtenaw United Way and its predecessor organizations, the Ypsilanti Community Chest, 1932-1971, and the Ann Arbor Community Chest, 1921-1971. Executive committee and board of directors minutes, manuals, reports, and scrapbooks containing clippings, photographs, and other organization papers.
18 linear feet
21 oversize volumes
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group (donor no. 7079 ) is on deposit from the Washtenaw United Way. The first accession was received from WUW executive director, Robert B. Kerschbaum in July 1984. Periodic additions to this record group have been received.
The record group is closed to research, except with the permission of the executive of WUW.
The Washtenaw United Way was formed in 1971 with the merger of the Ypsilanti and Ann Arbor Community Chest organizations. The Washtenaw United Way record group thus consists of materials from both the Ann Arbor and Ypsilanti chapters prior to the merger as well as records created by Washtenaw United Way since 1971.
The record group, as maintained, has two series: Ypsilanti and Washtenaw United Way. The Ypsilanti records cover the period, 1929-1971. The Washtenaw series includes material from the period, 1921-1971 when the organization was known as the Ann Arbor Community Chest, as well as material dated after 1971 when the organization broadened its geographic scope and merged with the Ypsilanti chapter.
The record group includes minutes of the board of directors and executive committee, agency manuals, and scrapbooks containing clippings, distributed campaign materials, and scattered photographs.
Subjects:
Ann Arbor United Fund.; Social service--Michigan--Washtenaw County--Societies, etc.; Washtenaw United Way.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Washtenaw United Way.
Contributors:
Ann Arbor Community Chest.; Ypsilanti Community Chest.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Scrapbooks.
- Ypsilanti Community Cheest
  - Volume containing: constitution and by-laws; board and budget manuals; and rosters (Box 1)
  - Board of Directors minutes, 1937-1971; 4 volumes (Box 1)
  - Volume containing: Annual meetings 1955-1971 and financial reports, 1934-1970 (Box 2)
  - Volume containing: Campaign goals and objectives 1930-1970 agency requests, allocations, and payment to agencies; and comparative agency allocations, 1946-1970 (Box 2)
  - Budget committee minutes, 1942-1971; 3 volumes (Box 2)
  - Planning committee minutes, 1959-1969 (Box 2)
  - Audit reports, 1944-1971 (Box 2)
  - Council of Social Agencies/Social Planning Committee of the Ypsilanti Community Fund
    - Constitution and bylaws; lists of officers (Box 3)
    - Annual reports, 1941-1958 (Box 3)
    - Minutes of meetings (Box 3)
    - Survey and reports, 3 folders (Box 3)
    - General, 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Financial reports, 1929-1933 (Box 3)
  - Campaign publicity, 1939-1970 (Box 3)
  - Loose items from scrapbooks, 6 folders (Box 3)
  - Scrapbooks (campaigns)
    - 1941-1942 (Box 4)
    - 1930-1951, mainly 1942-1951 (Box 4)
    - 1952 (Volume 1)
    - 1953 (Volume 2)
    - 1954 (Volume 3)
    - 1955 (Box 4)
    - 1956 (Box 4)
    - 1957 (Volume 4)
    - 1955-1958 (Volume 5)
    - 1958-1965 (Volume 6)
    - 1965-1971 (Volume 7)
- Washtenaw United Way
  (records dated before 1971 are of the Ann Arbor Community Chest)
  - Board of directors and executive committee
    - Minutes, 1921-2002
      - 1921-1959, 6 volumes; 2 folders (Box 5)
      - 1960-1969, 2 volumes; 3 folders (Box 6)
      - 1970-1974, 10 volumes (Box 7)
      - 1975-1979, 10 volumes (Box 8)
      - 1980-1984, 10 volumes (Box 12)
      - 1985-1987, 6 volumes (Box 13)
      - 1988-1989, 5 volumes (Box 14)
      - 1990-1992, 6 volumes (Box 15)
      - 1993-1995, 6 volumes (Box 16)
      - 1996-1999, 7 volumes (Box 17)
        (1997 executive committee minutes not received)
      - 2001-2002, 4 volumes (Box 18)
  - Administrative and subject files
    - Budget files, 1969-1973; 5 volumes; 1 folders (Box 9)
    - Planning committee files, 1962-1970; 2 folders (Box 10)
    - Council of Social Agencies files, 1945-1962; 8 folders (Box 10)
    - Chest Board manual, 1948-1951 (Box 10)
    - Miscellaneous reports (Box 10)
  - Scrapbooks
    - Campaigns
      - 1933-1938 (Box 11)
      - 1939-1939 (Box 11)
      - 1942-1946 (Box 11)
      - 1947-1952 (Volume 8)
      - 1953-1956 (Volume 9)
      - 1957 (Box 11)
      - 1962-1963 (Volume 10)
      - 1964-1965 (Volume 11)
      - 1966 (Box 11)
      - 1966-1968 (Volume 12)
      - 1969-1970 (Volume 13)
      - 1971-1973/74 (Volume 14)
      - 1973/74-1974/75 (Volume 15)
      - 1975-1976 (Volume 16)
      - 1976-1977 (Volume 17)
      - 1978-1979 (Volume 18)
      - 1980-1981 (Volume 19)
    - Scrapbooks (general)
      - 1946-1968 (Volume 20)
      - 1968-1973 (Volume 21)
    - Loose items from scrapbooks nos. 8-21 (Box 11)
    - Social Service seminar, 1938-1939 (Box 11)